Let's use the years we walked together as a springboard.
Didorong maju oleh tahun yang dihabiskan bersama.
And move forward full speed without slowing down!
Maju dengan kecepatan penuh tanpa memperlambat kecepatan.
The clue to an unseen case
Sebuah fatamorgana yang tampak
is seen in a mysterious mirage.
memicu sebuah kasus yang tak terlihat.
He sees through the one and only truth.
Dia melihat satu-satunya kebenaran.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
Memiliki penampilan seorang anak kecil dengan kepintaran orang dewasa.
His name is Detective Conan!
Namanya adalah Detektif Conan!
"The Angel Disappears into the Mirage"
"Fatamorgana dari Malaikat yang Menghilang!"
"Mouri Detective Agency"
"Kantor Detektif Mouri"
I see.
Begitu.
So, you want me to look for your missing husband?
Kau ingin aku menemukan suamimu yang hilang.
Yes. This is my husband, Satoru Aoki.
Ya. Ini adalah suamiku, Satoru Aoki.
He's an artist,
Aoki adalah seorang seniman.
and there were times in the past,
Dia pergi untuk melukis
when he would go off painting without telling me where he was going.
sebelumnya tanpa memberitahuku ke mana dia akan pergi.
But he never failed to report back
Tapi dia selalu melaporkan perkembangannya.
He would send me photos of the canvas every day.
Dia akan mengirim foto-foto kanvasnya setiap hari.
I see. And that stopped the day before yesterday.
Begitu. Dan itu berhenti kemarin lusa.
Yes. This is the last photo I received.
Ya. Ini gambar terakhir yang kuterima.
How beautiful.
Itu indah.
But there's something strange about the photo.
Tapi itu sebuah lukisan yang aneh.
Which means?
Bagaimana maksudmu?
He's an artist that draws only
Aoki hanya melukis apa yang dia lihat dengan matanya sendiri.
But that painting doesn't look to be anything of this world, does it?
Tapi lukisan itu seperti dunia lain.
True. Maybe he changed his painting style.
Benar. Apa dia mengubah gayanya?
I got it! I know where Mr. Aoki is!
Aku tahu di mana Aoki.
What a beautiful ocean!
Airnya indah!
Are you sure it's here?
Kau yakin ini tempatnya?
Yep. The bluish white waves that were in that painting
Yah. Ombak biru yang dia lukis
is a natural phenomenon called "Glowing Firefly Squid"
adalah fenomena alam yang disebut "Bunuh diri cumi kunang-kunang."
The phenomenon of the school of bluish white firefly squid
Sekelompok cumi kunang-kunang yang bersinar
being washed up to shore is exclusive only to Toyama Bay.
hanya terdampar di Teluk Toyama.
And recently, it was sighted at this beach!
Terakhir diamati di pantai ini.
You're very knowledgeable, aren't you?
Kau sangat berpengetahuan.
I... I saw it on TV.
Aku... aku melihatnya di TV.
Oh boy.
Astaga.
But, how do we look for him from here?
Tapi bagaimana kita akan menemukan dia sekarang?
Let's go search every lodging nearby.
Kita akan mulai dengan memeriksa penginapan-penginapan terdekat.
Dear!
Sayang!
The victim is artist Mr. Satoru Aoki, age 52.
Korban adalah pelukis Satoru Aoki, berusia 52 tahun.
I see. His identity was specified quite speedily, no?
Begitu. Kau mengidentifikasi dia cukup cepat.
Yes. Well, you see...
Ya, karena...
His wife just happened to be here looking for him,
istrinya datang ke sini mencarinya dengan seorang detektif.
Hello, I'm Detective Kogoro Mouri.
Aku Detektif Kogoro Mouri.
Mouri?
Mouri?
You mean the Sleeping Kogoro?
Kogoro Tidur itu?
Did he drown to death?
Apa dia tenggelam?
Yes, most probably.
Mungkin.
His estimate tine of death is between 20:00 to 23:00 yesterday.
Dia tewas semalam antara pukul 8 dan 11.
The sea was rough last night, wasn't it?
Lautnya deras semalam.
Yes, sir.
Ya.
And moreover, this was found in the pocket of the corpse.
Dan kami menemukan ini dalam jaketnya.
You mean he was drunk?
Jadi dia mabuk.
According to Mrs. Aoki,
Menurut istrinya,
it seems that Mr. Aoki had a bad leg
Aoki memiliki satu kaki yang lemah.
and was dragged it along when walking.
Dia menyeret satu kakinya selagi dia berjalan.
He was probably drunk, slipped and fell into the sea.
Dia mungkin tersandung dan jatuh ke dalam laut.
-No. -Huh?
-Sebenarnya... -Peliknya.
He has what looks like a bruise on his cheek.
Pria ini memiliki memar di pipinya.
See.
Lihat.
Did he bruise himself when he fell into the sea?
Dia mungkin mendapatkannya ketika dia jatuh ke dalam laut.
Well, there's a possibility that he was punched by someone.
Mungkin seseorang memukulnya.
-Yes. -Not you again. Stay put!
-Ya. -Berkeliaran di sekitar tempat kejadian lagi?
Who is that?
Siapa itu?
A local fisherman called Ishiguro.
Seorang nelayan lokal bernama Ishiguro.
He's a hard worker, but prone to violence.
Dia pekerja keras, tapi dia banyak berkelahi.
Hello.
Permisi.
I'm from the police. I contacted you earlier.
Kami polisi yang menghubungimu tadi.
Yes. It's true that Mr. Aoki from about 2 weeks ago
Ya. Aoki tinggal di sini sejak dua minggu yang lalu.
But I had no idea that he had passed away.
Aku tidak tahu dia meninggal.
If you will excuse me then.
Beritahu aku jika kau butuh sesuatu.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Huh? The painting's gone!
Hah? Tidak ada lukisan.
I found it! Mr. Aoki's painting.
Aku menemukan lukisan Aoki.
But, why is it in there?
Apa yang sedang dilakukan di dalam sana?
Sunlight, dust and temperature change are adverse to oil painting!
Cahaya matahari, debu dan perubahan suhu buruk untuk lukisan minyak.
That's probably why he stored it like this, no?
Mungkin itu sebabnya dia menyimpannya di sini.
It's the same painting that he sent me a photo of.
Itu lukisan yang dia kirimkan padaku.
Nope. Look.
Tidak, lihat.
Something's been drawn onto it.
Dia menambahkan sesuatu.
Huh?
Apa?
True. There's something in the sky.
Kau benar. Ada sesuatu di langit.
I think it's our house.
Mungkinkah itu rumah kami?
It does look similar.
Itu terlihat mirip.
Doesn't this one look like an angel ascending to the sky?
Bukankah ini tampak seperti malaikat yang naik ke langit?
So, the white one below
Warna putih di bawahnya
is a soul that is guided along by the angel?
pastilah jiwa yang dituntun oleh malaikat itu.
But Mr. Aoki only drew things
Tapi kupikir Aoki hanya melukis apa yang dia lihat.
He was probably drunk and hallucinated.
Dia mungkin sedang mabuk dan berhalusinasi.
Maybe he had a hunch
Mungkin dia memprediksi
that he would be ascending to heaven.
dia akan segera dipanggil ke surga.
That's my husband's digital camera.
Itu kamera digital Aoki.
He always took photos of the things he drew.
Dia memfoto semua yang dia lukis.
And he painted while looking at the photos he took.
Dia melukis dari foto-foto itu.
May I see that?
Coba kulihat!
Okay.
Baik.
Just as I thought!
Aku tahu itu!
Just what're you doing?
Apa yang sedang kau lakukan?
It's been deleted!
Foto yang dia gambar sudah dihapus!
What?
Apa?
The "Glowing firefly squid" phenomenon
Bunuh diri cumi kunang-kunang
occurred at night 10 days ago.
terjadi 10 hari yang lalu.
The data for that day is all gone.
Tidak ada data dari hari itu.
True. 10 days ago...
Kau benar. 10 hari yang lalu...
The folder for May 6th is gone.
Tidak ada berkas untuk tanggal 6 Mei.
Huh? The data in the digital camera's been deleted?
Apa? Data kamera digitalnya sudah dihapus?
Yes. Do you recall anything?
Ya. Kau ingat sesuatu?
Come to think of it, yesterday night...
Dipikir-pikir, semalam sekitar tengah malam...
Yes?
Ya?
Mr. Aoki?
Aoki?
The victim was supposedly already dead by then.
Korban sudah tewas pada saat itu.
It's most likely that the person you saw was not Mr. Aoki
Mungkin yang kau lihat bukanlah Aoki,
but rather the who killed him.
tapi pria yang membunuhnya.
Why didn't you notice back then?
Kenapa kau tidak menyadarinya?
I'm sorry.
Maafkan aku.
It was dark.
Saat itu gelap.
And besides, he was dragging his leg,
Dia menyeret satu kakinya,
so I just assumed it was him.
jadi kupikir itu dia.
No doubt about it.
Pasti itu.
The perp disguised himself as Mr. Aoki
Pembunuh menyamar dirinya sebagai korban
and came to delete the photos
dan datang untuk menghapus foto itu.
because there was something he didn't want anyone to see.
Sesuatu yang memberatkan pasti ada dalam foto itu.
-I got it! -What?
-Aku tahu! -Apa?
That person was probably a psychic!
Mereka pasti cenayang.
Huh? Just what're you talking about?
Apa? Apa yang sedang kau bicarakan?
Because that person went straight to Mr. Aoki's room, right?
Mereka langsung ke kamar Aoki, bukan?
He wouldn't have know where the room was
Hanya cenayang yang tahu di mana kamarnya.
True.
Kau benar.
It would've been impossible
Dengan kamar-kamar lain di sini,
to go straight to his room when there are other rooms, too.
mustahil untuk langsung menuju yang itu.
In other words, the perp is
Jadi sang pembunuh
someone who had visited Mr. Aoki in his room before!
pernah mengunjungi kamar Aoki sebelumnya.
Mrs. Aoki looked really depressed.
Istrinya tampak cukup depresi.
I wonder if it was okay to send her home alone.
Haruskah kita membiarkan dia pulang sendirian?
Well, after all, her husband passed away.
Bagaimanapun, suaminya tewas.
She can't help it.
Pasti dia sedih.
All we need to do now is get the perp.
Kita hanya harus menemukan siapa pelakunya.
What?
Apa?
I already told the police about it just a while ago.
Aku baru saja memberitahu polisi tentang itu.
No. I'm not with them.
Sebenarnya, aku tidak bersama mereka.
Mrs. Aoki asked you to follow
Istrinya memintamu
the final tracks of her husband for her, right?
untuk melacak jejak terakhir suaminya, bukan?
Yeah.
Yah.
If so...
Jika begitu...
Yes, I met Mr. Aoki.
Yah, aku bertemu Aoki.
I've been searching for my missing girlfriend for sometime
Aku sedang mencari kekasihku yang hilang.
and I went to the inn he was staying at the day before yesterday, too.
Aku mengunjungi hotel itu kemarin lusa
To pass out these flyers.
untuk membagikan selebaran ini.
Your cooperation would be most appreciated.
Aku hargai bantuanmu.
It must be hard, but hang in there, okay?
Aku tahu itu sulit, tapi jangan menyerah.
Yes, thank you very much.
Benar. Terima kasih.
Sorry.
Permisi.
It's no use already.
Dia sudah lama pergi.
Forget it already.
Menyerahlah.
What?
Apa katamu?
I was pissed!
Itu membuatku marah!
But I haven't seen him since then.
Tapi aku tidak melihatnya sejak itu.
I see.
Begitu.
Yes. I met him at sundown the day before yesterday.
Ya. Aku melihatnya dua malam yang lalu.
I was talking a walk on the beach back then
Aku sedang berjalan menyusuri pantai
to see the famous mirage here.
untuk menyaksikan fatamorgana yang terkenal itu.
That's when...
Ketika itulah...
He looked to be deeply troubled.
Dia tampak sedang berpikir,
It seemed as if he was contemplating suicide or something.
sepertinya dia sedang memikirkan bunuh diri.
So, I called out to him.
Jadi aku bicara padanya.
We happen to hit it off well together, you see.
Kami cukup akur.
So, we spent the entire night drinking in his room till morning.
Malam itu kami mabuk di kamarnya.
Is that so?
Benarkah?
Hey, hey. This is...
Hei, apa ini...
Hey, sonny!
Hei, nak!
You shouldn't look into other people's bags without permission.
Kau tak bisa memeriksa barang orang lain.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
I wonder if Mr. Aoki committed suicide.
Apa Aoki bunuh diri?
Huh?
Hah?
I'd like these please.
Aku menginginkan ini.
Gifts for your family?
Apa mereka hadiah untuk keluargamu?
Yes, for my wife and daughter.
Ya, untuk istri dan putriku.
And, what did you want?
Apa itu?
The last person is you.
Kau orang terakhir.
I met him yesterday morning
Aku melihatnya kemarin pagi
when I went to deliver fresh fish to the inn.
ketika aku sedang mengantar ikan segar ke hotel.
What? That customer didn't even touch the food.
Apa? Dia tidak menyentuhnya sama sekali!
Sorry. He says he has no appetite.
Maaf. Dia hanya tidak menginginkannya.
What? Where's that guy?
Apa? Di mana dia?
They are gifts from the sea
Kami nelayan
that we fishermen stake our lives to get a hold of.
mempertaruhkan nyawa kami untuk menangkap itu!
I can't stand somebody being wasteful like this!
Aku tak bisa duduk diam selagi seseorang menyia-nyiakannya!
That's why you went to his room to bawl him out?
Jadi kau pergi ke kamarnya?
Yeah, but I didn't lay a finger on him.
Ya, tapi aku tidak menyentuhnya.
How'd you get that wound?
Dari mana kau mendapat bekas luka itu?
Huh? Oh, this...
Apa? Ini?
I had an accident at sea three years ago
Aku terlibat sebuah kecelakaan di laut tiga tahun lalu.
and I can't move it well since then.
Sejak itu, aku tidak punya kendali penuh.
Just who's the perp anyway?
Siapa yang melakukannya?
None of the three have alibis for the day of the crime.
Tak satupun dari mereka punya alibi.
Is this a homicide to begin with?
Lagipula, apa ini benar-benar sebuah pembunuhan?
Or an accident? Suicide?
Atau sebuah kecelakaan? Atau bunuh diri?
Darn it! I'm totally lost!
Sial! Aku tidak tahu!
Huh? Those people...
Hah? Orang-orang di sana...
I wonder what they're looking at?
Apa yang sedang mereka lihat?
Probably the spring mirage.
Mungkin fatamorgana musim semi.
Uozu is famous for mirages, you see.
Uozu terkenal untuk fatamorgananya juga.
Mirage?
Fatamorgana?
Maybe that was...
Mungkinkah itu...
If so...
Jika itu benar, maka...
I pooped. I'm exhausted.
Aku lelah!
After all, we've been walking around all day.
Kita berjalan seharian.
And, did you find him at all?
Apa kau sudah menemukan
The perp who deleted the video from Mr. Aoki's camera?
orang yang menghapus video dari kamera Aoki?
No, unfortunately not yet.
Sayangnya, tidak.
Is that so?
Begitu.
Here, it's almost ready.
Sudah siap.
It looks delicious.
Ini tampak lezat!
I fished them this afternoon, you see.
Aku menangkap ikan-ikan ini siang ini.
You go out to fish, too?
Benarkah? Kau juga memancing?
Sometimes.
Terkadang.
I used to be a fisherman before, you see.
Aku dulu seorang nelayan.
Then, please tell me.
Maka aku punya sebuah pertanyaan.
Does Mr. Ishiguro always wear a black cap
Apa Ishiguro selalu mengenakan topi hitam di laut?
Yeah, he says that it's his lucky charm.
Ya. Dia menyebut itu jimat keberuntungannya.
Really?
Benarkah?
Oh, that's right!
Oh, benar.
Before returning to Tokyo,
Sebelum kau pergi,
why not go and watch the late night firefly squid fishing?
kenapa tidak melihat mereka memancing cumi kunang-kunang di malam hari?
The sea glows blue and it's really romantic.
Lautan menjadi biru. Itu sangat romantis.
What a bother.
Menyusahkan.
Oh, come on, let's go!
Kenapa tidak? Ayo kia pergi!
-Right, Conan? -Huh?
-Benar, Conan? -Hah?
Yeah!
Ya!
Wait, sir.
Hei, tuan.
Huh?
Hah?
What is it?
Ada apa?
Pops Kogoro asked me to tell you...
Kogoro menyuruhku untuk melakukan sesuatu.
I see.
Begitu.
Got it. I'll keep an eye out.
Mengerti. Aku akan mengawasi.
Please do.
Terima kasih.
Hey, it's 2:00 after midnight, you know.
Pukul 2 dini hari.
Are we really going?
Apa kita sungguh akan pergi?
The boat's leaving at 3:00.
Mereka berangkat pukul 3.
Come on, hurry, let's go!
Ayo, mari kita pergi.
I'm counting on you, okay?
Aku mengandalkanmu.
Sure thing. Be careful.
Tentu. Hati-hatilah.
That's it!
Kau tertangkap!
You're...
Kau...
Mr. Mouri, is he really the perp?
Mouri, apa dia sungguh pembunuhnya?
Huh?
Apa?
You said so, didn't you? That the perp would be coming.
Kau memberitahu kami pembunuhnya akan datang.
Hot pot, beer, and sake...
Pot, bir, dan sake...
So, this is the Sleeping Kogoro?
Apa ini yang dimaksud Kogoro Tidur?
I set a trap a while ago.
Aku mengatur sebuah jebakan untuk pembunuhnya.
And told the perp that if we return to Tokyo,
Aku memberi tahu pembunuhnya bahwa jika aku kembali ke Tokyo,
maybe it would be possible to recover the deleted digital camera data.
aku bisa mendapatkan kembali data yang dihapus.
So, I kept everyone away from this room.
Itu sebabnya aku menjauhkan semua orang dari ruangan ini.
Then, the perp appeared just as expected.
Dan pembunuhnya muncul.
Correct?
Bukankah itu benar,
Owner of this inn, Mr. Taro Hayashi?
manajer hotel Taro Hayashi?
Just what're you talking about?
Apa yang sedang kau bicarakan?
I was just trying to protect the camera as I was told to.
Aku melindungi kamera seperti yang kau minta.
The perp of this case needed to satisfy two conditions.
Pembunuhnya harus memenuhi dua syarat.
First, he had to be left-handed
Pertama, dia harus kidal.
and in addition, be able to operate a boat!
Kedua, dia harus bisa mengoperasikan sebuah perahu.
Huh?
Apa?
The corpse had a punch bruise on his right cheek.
Seseorang memukul korban di pipi kanannya.
In other words,
Dengan kata lain,
it means he was punched from the front with a left hand.
dia mendapatkan pukulan tangan kiri di wajahnya.
But, what with the operating a boat?
Tapi bagaimana tentang mengoperasikan sebuah perahu?
The perp had deleted the data from Mr. Aoki's camera.
Pembunuh menghapus data dari kamera Aoki.
In other words, a clue leading to the perp
Dengan kata lain, ada bukti yang mengarah
was drawn in the painting, which was based on the data.
pada pembunuh tersebut dalam foto itu.
Ran, bring the painting.
Ran, lukisannya.
Yes, sir.
Baik.
You may have all thought that
Kami percaya
this painting described an illusionary drawing of a soul
lukisan itu menggambarkan sebuah halusinasi
ascending to heaven guided along by an angel.
sesosok malaikat yang menuntun sebuah jiwa menuju surga.
But Mr. Aoki was an artist who only drew things
Tapi Aoki hanya menggambar apa yang dia lihat.
This was actually reality after all!
Maka, itu pasti nyata.
What? But no matter how you look at it, just cannot be real.
Apa? Tapi itu terlihat sangat palsu.
It's a mirage.
Itu sebuah fatamorgana.
Mirage?
Sebuah fatamorgana?
The air near the surface of the water is cooled,
Di musim semi, udara dekat permukaan air mendingin
and becomes dense during the mirage in spring.
dan menjadi padat.
Light refracts and on top of the actual scenery,
Cahaya dibiaskan, menyebabkan fatamorgana
a virtual upside down image called superior mirage appears.
yang mencerminkan pemandangan sebenarnya secara terbalik muncul.
In other words, if you turn the painting upside down,
Dengan kata lain, jika kau membalik lukisannya,
the actual image that is still not drawn will become visible.
kau akan melihat apa yang sebenarnya terjadi.
This is...
Ini adalah...
Right.
Ya.
The white house that is depicted there is a white fishing boat.
Rumah putih yang dilukis di sana adalah sebuah perahu memancing.
The angel ascending to heaven
Malaikat yang terbang ke langit
is a woman that was pushed into the sea.
adalah seorang wanita yang didorong ke laut.
And the soul that is drawn below it
Dan jiwa di bawahnya
is the white cap of the perp.
adalah topi putih milik pembunuhnya.
In other words, this painting was
Dengan kata lain, lukisan ini
a drawing of a dreadful murder being committed!
menggambarkan pembunuhan yang mengerikan.
After redrawing his painting several times,
Selagi meninjau lukisannya,
Mr. Aoki probably realized what had actually happened.
Aoki pasti telah menyadari kebenaran itu.
Mr. Aoki told Mr. Akagi to forget about his girlfriend
Dia memberitahu Akagi untuk menyerah terhadap kekasihnya,
stared at the sea with a solemn look
menatap dalam ke lautan,
and couldn't eat his breakfast because he lost his appetite,
dan tidak punya selera untuk sarapan karena itu.
Then, who is the woman that was killed?
Siapa wanita yang dibunuh?
The glowing firefly squid that were drawn in the painting
Bunuh diri cumi kunang-kunang dalam lukisan itu
was seen 10 days ago.
terjadi 10 hari yang lalu.
Mr. Akagi's girlfriend went missing the same day.
Kekasih Akagi menghilang di hari yang sama.
Judging from her hairstyle and clothes,
Berdasarkan potongan rambut dan pakaiannya,
there's probably no doubt about it.
itu mungkin dia.
Mr. Aoki was killed because he found out about this.
Aoki dibunuh karena dia menyadari ini.
In other words, the perp is someone who is left-handed
Pembunuhnya pasti pria kidal
and able to operate a boat.
yang bisa mengoperasikan sebuah perahu.
Mr. Akagi who was passing out the flyers with his left hand
Akagi membagikan selebaran dengan tangan kirinya.
is left handed but cannot operate a boat.
Dia kidal, tapi tak bisa mengoperasikan sebuah kapal.
Mr. Shirakawa locked the trunk with his right hand.
Shirakawa mengunci kopernya dengan tangan kanannya.
Mr. Ishiguro who is also able to operate a boat
Ishiguro, yang bisa mengoperasikan perahu,
cannot use his left hand.
tak punya kendali penuh atas tangan kirinya.
And when he goes to sea, he wears a black hat.
Dan ketika dia pergi ke laut, dia mengenakan sebuah topi hitam.
In other words,
Dengan kata lain,
the person who knew that Mr. Aoki was staying in this room...
satu-satunya pria yang tahu Aoki tinggal di kamar ini
The person who satisfied these two conditions...
dan memenuhi persyaratan ini
That person is the one who held chopsticks using his left hand
adalah pria yang memegang sumpitnya di tangan kiri
and served us fish that he himself caught.
dan menunjukkan pada kita ikan yang dia tangkap sendiri.
The owner of this inn!
Manajer hotel!
You're the only one who fits!
Cuma kau yang bisa!
But that's not enough to...
Tapi itu tidak cukup untuk...
You mentioned earlier, didn't you?
Tadi kau menyebutkan...
And, did you find him at all?
Apa kau sudah menemukan
The perp who deleted the video from Mr. Aoki's camera?
orang yang menghapus video dari kamera Aoki?
It's true that the digital camera can also take videos.
Kamera itu bisa merekam video.
But, how did you know that a video was deleted and not photos?
Tapi bagaimana kau tahu bahwa video yang telah dihapus dan bukan foto?
The ones who know that are, the late Mr. Aoki
Hanya mendiang Aoki dan pria
and the one who deleted the data... the perp!
yang menghapus data itu yang akan tahu.
Then, what about him having seen a suspicious character?
Bagaimana dengan sosok mencurigakan yang kita lihat?
It's probably an imaginary character
Sesosok orang khayalan
that he made up to keep from being suspected.
untuk mengalihkan kecurigaan menjauh dari dirinya.
It was an accident at first.
Awalnya, itu sebuah kecelakaan.
I didn't think I was being filmed.
Aku tidak berpikir ada orang yang sedang merekam.
He tried to persuade me to turn myself in.
Dia menyuruhku untuk menyerahkan diri.
He told me to atone for my crime.
Untuk menebus dosa.
That's why...
Itu sebabnya...
I thought I got rid of all the evidence and yet...
Aku pikir aku sudah menghapus semua bukti.
Darn it!
Sial!
Thank you so very much.
Terima kasih banyak.
Please cheer up.
Cerialah.
Mr. Aoki helped us solve the case.
Aoki membantu kami memecahkan sebuah kasus.
Besides, I'm sure that Mr. Aoki also saved a certain person's life, too.
Di samping itu, kurasa dia menyelamatkan sebuah nyawa.
Huh?
Apa?
What do you mean, Conan?
Apa maksudmu, Conan?
Mr. Shirakawa...
Maksudku Shirakawa.
He said he came to see the mirage
Dia datang untuk melihat fatamorgana itu,
and yet, he was empty-handed without binoculars or a camera, right?
tapi dia tidak punya teropong ataupun kamera.
And the only thing that was in his trunk
Dia hanya punya dua botol pil tidur di dalam tasnya.
I think that Mr. Shirakawa probably
Dia mungkin pergi ke Uozu untuk bunuh diri.
But he was buying gifts for his family at the hotel, right?
Tapi dia membelikan hadiah untuk keluarganya di hotel.
That's proof that he decided not to commit suicide.
Itu bukti dia sudah berubah pikiran.
That's why I think that Mr. Aoki was the one who made Mr. Aoki
Aoki mungkin telah mencegahnya bunuh diri.
I see! I'm sure that's it!
Begitu. Kau benar!
Yep! I guess so. I'm sure that's it.
Kau benar. Aku yakin itu.
"Next Episode"
"Episode Selanjutnya"
Rikumichi Kusuda?
Rikumichi Kusuda?
Oh, you mean the spy from the Organization that snuck into the hospital
Mata-mata organisasi yang menyusup
where Reina Mizunashi was staying.
ke rumah sakit Reina Mizunashi.
And, what about that?
Kenapa dengannya?
Please tell the people at the FBI
Beritahu FBI untuk merahasiakannya.
One of the guys of the Organization, Bourbon...
Pria organisasi Borbon...
Tohru Amuro is sniffing around, you see!
Tohru Amuro sedang melakukan sebuah penyelidikan.
Next Conan, "The Scarlet Prelude"
Selanjutnya dalam Conan, "Prolog Scarlet"
Next Conan's Hint:
Petunjuk Conan Selanjutnya:
"An answer sheet"
"Sebuah lembar jawaban"
Did someone say "pro"? Did they mean me?
Apa seseorang mengatakan "pro"? Apa maksud mereka aku?
I don't have time for you!
Aku tidak punya waktu untukmu!